this problem
asks us to write a program named.rb
that asks the user to type in their name
and then prints out a greeting message
with the name included
so i've got my file name.rb open
and the first thing we want to do is
just display a message to the user
i'm going to hop over to my terminal and
run my code
and i see the prompt that i want to
display to the user
going back to my name.rb file now i need
to
get some input from the user i'm going
to store that user input in a local
variable called
name and i can use the get
s method to get that user input
you can think of that as getstring
this method will pause program execution
and wait for the user to press the enter
key when they do
program execution will continue now
typically when
we are soliciting some user input we
will want to chain the chomp method
on to get s when the user presses the
enter key to
submit their input and continue program
execution
a new line character is added to the end
of that user input
calling the chomp method on that user
input
will remove that newline character
so let's run our program again this time
after we display our message to the user
program execution pauses
so now i have a chance to put in a name
and when i press the enter key the
program continues
the last step of this problem is to
output a greeting to the user with their
name
so on line three i'll call put us
use string concatenation to display a
greeting
with the user's name
let's try this out
and we see the expected behavior